[
  {
    "id": "1",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Define AWS Cloud",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Why is AWS more economical than traditional data centers for applications with varying compute workloads?",
      "answers": ["Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) costs are billed on a monthly basis.", "Customers retain full administrative access to their Amazon EC2 instances.",
        "Amazon EC2 instances can be launched on-demand when needed.", "Customers can permanently run enough instances to handle peak workloads."],
      "correctAnswer": ["Amazon EC2 instances can be launched on-demand when needed."]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "2",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Define AWS Cloud",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Which AWS service would simplify migration of a database to AWS?",
      "answers": ["AWS Storage Gateway", "AWS Database Migration Service (AWS DMS)",
        "Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2)", "Amazon AppStream 2.0"],
      "correctAnswer": ["AWS Database Migration Service (AWS DMS)"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "3",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Define AWS Cloud",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Which AWS offering enables customers to find, buy, and immediately start using software solutions in their AWS environment?",
      "answers": ["AWS Config", "AWS OpsWorks",
        "AWS SDK", "AWS Marketplace"],
      "correctAnswer": ["AWS Marketplace"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "4",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Define AWS Cloud",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Which AWS networking service enables a company to create a virtual network within AWS?",
      "answers": ["AWS Config", "Amazon Route 53",
        "AWS Direct Connect", "Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (Amazon VPC)"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (Amazon VPC)"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "5",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Define AWS Cloud",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Which of the following is AWS's responsibility under the AWS shared responsibility model?",
      "answers": ["Configuring third-party applications", "Maintaining physical hardware",
        "Securing application access and data", "Managing custom Amazon Machine Images (AMIs)"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Maintaining physical hardware"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "6",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Define AWS Cloud",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Which component of AWS global infrastructure does Amazon CloudFront use to ensure low-latency delivery?",
      "answers": ["AWS Regions", "AWS edge locations",
        "AWS Availability Zones", "Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (Amazon VPC)"],
      "correctAnswer": ["AWS edge locations"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "7",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Define AWS Cloud",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "How would a system administrator add an additional layer of login security to a user's AWS Management Console?",
      "answers": ["Use AWS Cloud Directory", "Audit AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) roles",
        "Enable Multi-Factor Authentication", "Enable AWS CloudTrail"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Enable Multi-Factor Authentication"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "8",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Define AWS Cloud",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Which service can identify the user that made the API call when an Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instance is terminated?",
      "answers": ["Amazon CloudWatch", "AWS CloudTrail",
        "AWS X-Ray", "AWS Identity and Access Management (AWS IAM)"],
      "correctAnswer": ["AWS CloudTrail"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "9",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Define AWS Cloud",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Which service would you use to send alerts based on Amazon CloudWatch alarms?",
      "answers": ["Amazon Simple Notification Service (Amazon SNS)", "AWS CloudTrail",
        "AWS Trusted Advisor", "Amazon Route 53"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Amazon Simple Notification Service (Amazon SNS)"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "10",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Define AWS Cloud",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Where can a customer find information about prohibited actions on AWS infrastructure?",
      "answers": ["AWS Trusted Advisor", "AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM)",
        "AWS Billing Console", "AWS Acceptable Use Policy"],
      "correctAnswer": ["AWS Acceptable Use Policy"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "11",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Security",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 2",
      "question": "In the Shared Responsibility Model, which of the following are an example of 'Security in the cloud?'(Choose 2)",
      "answers": ["Physical security of the facilities in which the services operate", "In which country the content is stored",
        "Which AWS services are used with the content", "Protecting the global infrastructure", "Compliance with the computer security standards and regulations"],
      "correctAnswer": ["In which country the content is stored", "Which AWS services are used with the content"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "12",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Security",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "What does AWS recommend as the best practice for the AWS Account Root User after initial login?'",
      "answers": ["Delete root user access keys", "Delete root user account",
        "Restrict permissions on root user account", "Revoke all permissions on root user account"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Delete root user access keys"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "13",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Security",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 2",
      "question": "Which of the following are resources that AWS provides to customers as guidance to secure their data in the cloud? (Choose 2)",
      "answers": ["AWS Trusted Advisor", "AWS Security Learning Path",
        "Customer Testimonials", "Certified Partner Solutions", "AWS Enterprise Support"],
      "correctAnswer": ["AWS Trusted Advisor", "AWS Enterprise Support"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "14",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Security",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 2",
      "question": "Which of the following are some of the security benefits that AWS offers? (Choose 2)",
      "answers": ["Meet compliance requirements", "Data storage",
        "Shared Collaboration Model", "Secure Global Infrastructure", "Inventory and Application Management"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Meet compliance requirements", "Secure Global Infrastructure"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "15",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Security",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "In the Shared Responsibility Model, for which aspect of securing the cloud is AWS responsible?",
      "answers": ["Security for the cloud", "Security to the cloud",
        "Security in the cloud", "Security of the cloud"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Security of the cloud"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "16",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Security",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 2",
      "question": "Which of the following are included in AWS Assurance Programs? (Choose 2)",
      "answers": ["Industry Best Practices", "Partner Validations",
        "Certification/Attestations", "Laws, Regulation, and Privacy", "Customer testimonials"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Industry Best Practices", "Certification/Attestations"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "17",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Security",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a feature of AWS Identity and Access Management?",
      "answers": ["Manage federated users and their permissions", "Manage users and their access",
        "Manage roles and their permissions", "Manage services and their capabilities"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Manage services and their capabilities"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "18",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Security",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "What is AWS Trusted Advisor?",
      "answers": ["Partner program that helps you validate your application deployment", "Professional Services offering that helps you migrate to cloud",
        "AWS service that helps you manage access to your account", "Online tool that helps you configure resources to follow best practices"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Online tool that helps you configure resources to follow best practices"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "19",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Security",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 2",
      "question": "When creating an IAM policy, what are the two types of access that can be granted to a user? (Choose 2)",
      "answers": ["Authorized Access", "Programmatic Access",
        "Administrative Root Access", "AWS Management Console Access", "Institutional Access"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Programmatic Access", "AWS Management Console Access"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "20",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Security",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 3",
      "question": "The AWS Risk and Compliance Program is made up of which of the following components? (Choose 3)",
      "answers": ["Physical Security", "Risk Management",
        "Identity Management", "Automation Environment", "Information Security", "Security Principles", "Control Environment"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Risk Management", "Identity Management", "Control Environment"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "21",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "What tool helps avoid limitations of being able to create new resources on-demand or scheduled?",
      "answers": ["CloudWatch", "Route 53",
        "Auto Scaling", "Elastic Load Balancer"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Auto Scaling"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "22",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the four areas of the performance efficiency pillar?",
      "answers": ["Tradeoffs", "Selection",
        "Tracability", "Monitoring"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Tracability"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "23",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Which of the following cloud security controls ensures that only authorized and authenticated users are able to access your resources?",
      "answers": ["Incident Response", "Infrastructure protection",
        "Identity and Access Management", "Detective Controls"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Identity and Access Management"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "24",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "In a physical data center, security is typically considered in what area?",
      "answers": ["In the closest availability zones", "In the closest region",
        "In an edge location", "Only in the perimeter"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Only in the perimeter"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "25",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "When considering cost optimization, what model allows you to pay only for what computing resources you actively use?",
      "answers": ["Consumption model", "Expenditure model",
        "Ecconomies of scale model", "Ecconomies of scope model"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Consumption model"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "26",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 2",
      "question": "Which design principles are recommended when considering performance efficiency? (Choose 2)",
      "answers": ["Enabling traceability", "Democratize advanced technologies",
        "Expenditure awareness", "Serverless architecture", "Matching supply with demand"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Democratize advanced technologies", "Serverless architecture"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "27",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT considered a fault tolerant tool?",
      "answers": ["SQS", "WAF",
        "S3", "RD"],
      "correctAnswer": ["RD"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "28",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 2",
      "question": "Which of the following are high availability characteristics of Amazon Route 53? (Choose 2)",
      "answers": ["Latency based routing", "Collect and track high latency metrics",
        "Geolocation routing", "Terminate instances based on specified conditions", "Mask failure of an instance/software"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Latency based routing", "Geolocation routing"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "29",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "What is defined as the ability for a system to remain operational even if some of the components of that system fail?",
      "answers": ["DNS Failovers", "High durability",
        "Fault tolerance", "High availability"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Fault tolerance"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "30",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "Which of the following describes Elastic Load Balancers (ELB)?",
      "answers": ["Translates domain names into IP addresses", "Distributes incoming traffic amongst your instances",
        "Launches or terminates instances based on specific conditions", "Creates new resources on demand"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Distributes incoming traffic amongst your instances"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "31",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What AWS service does the acronym ELB represent?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["Elastic Load Balancing"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "32",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What AWS service does the acronym IAM represent?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["Identity Access Management"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "33",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What AWS service does the acronym EIP represent?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["Elastic IP address"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "34",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What AWS service does the acronym ENI represent?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["EC2 Elastic Network Interface"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "35",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What AWS service does the acronym VPC represent?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["Virtual Private Cloud"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "36",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What AWS service does the acronym EC2 represent?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["Elastic Compute Cloud"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "37",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What AWS service does the acronym S3 represent?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["Simple Storage Service"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "38",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What AWS service does the acronym EBS represent?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["Elastic Block Store"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "39",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What AWS service does the acronym RDS represent?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["Relational Database Service"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "40",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What AWS service does the acronym SQS represent?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["Simple Queue Service"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "41",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What is the name of an AWS deployment tool for simple applications?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["Elastic Beanstalk"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "42",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What is the name of an AWS deployment tool for multilayer applications?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["OpsWorks"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "43",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What is the name of an AWS infrastructure automation and deployment tool?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["CloudFormation"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "44",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What is the name of an AWS inexpensive data archive solution?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["Glacier"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "45",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What is the name of an AWS proprietary NoSQL key-value database with limited but powerful options for queries?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["DynamoDB"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "46",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What AWS service observes a fleet of servers; replaces faulty servers, and increases/decreases the size of the fleet based on external triggers like CPU usage?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["EC2 auto-scaling groups"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "47",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "Architecting",
      "questionType": "text entry",
      "question": "What AWS service keeps track of metrics and triggers alarms when a threshold is reached?",
      "answers": [" "],
      "correctAnswer": ["CloudWatch"]
    }
  }
]
